我们会再见面的 先生
I'll see you again, Mister.
停 停 快停下
Stop! Stop that! stop it!
这是怎么了 伙计
What was all that about, mate?
嗯?
Eh?
出什么问题了
What's your problem?
好 总算停下来了
Right, just settle down now.
不好意思
Oh excuse.
抱歉
So sorry.
什么!
What?
什么?
什么?!
What!
神秘博士
2007 Children in Need 喜剧短片
时间冲撞
编剧：史蒂文·莫法特
你是谁
Who are you?
哦…太棒了
Oh, brilliant.
我是说 全乱套了
I mean, totally wrong.
情况紧急 整个宇宙会在五分钟内爆炸
Bit emergency, universe goes bang in five minutes,
不过…棒极了
but, brilliant.
我是博士 你是谁
I'm the Doctor. Who are you?
没错你是 你就是博士
Yes, you are. You are the Doctor.
没错 我就是博士
Yes, I am. I'm the Doctor.
哦…你好啊 博士
Oh, good for you, Doctor.
机智的老博士
Good for brilliant old you.
你脑子没毛病吧
Is there something wrong with you?
喔 又出现了 这幅愁眉苦脸表情
Oh, there it goes, the frowny face.
我记得清清楚楚
I remember that one.
话说你…
Mind you,
皮肤比原来松弛了点儿
bit saggier than I ought to be.
头发也白了点
Hair's a bit greyer.
不过这都是我的缘故
That's because of me, though.
我们两个同时出现 缩短了时间差
The two of us together has shorted out the time differential.
送你回去后 一切都会恢复正常的
Should all snap back in place when we get you home.
到时又能把外套扣起来了
Be able to close that coat again.
先不管那些 瞧瞧你
But never mind that. Look at you!
这帽子 这外套 这一身板球范儿
The coat, the crickety cricket stuff,
这根芹菜…
the stick of celery.
芹菜…很大胆的选择
Yeah. Brave choice, celery,
不过还蛮适合你的
but fair play to you.
没几个人能在胸前戴"礼菜"的啊
Not a lot of men can carry off a decorative vegetable.
住口
Shut up!
我的塔迪斯出大问题了
There is something very wrong with my Tardis,
我必须马上想办法解决
and I've got to do something about it very, very quickly,
现在…说真的
and it would help, it really would help
如果没有某个皮包骨的白痴挡在面前
if there wasn't some skinny idiot ranting in my face
见到什么都大呼小叫 我会谢天谢地的!
about every single thing that happens to be in front of him!
哦 好的 抱歉…
Oh. Okay. Sorry.
博士
Doctor.
多谢
Thank you.
哦! 我的后脑勺!
Oh, the back of my head.
什么?
What?
抱歉 有点激动 毕竟这不是每天都能看到这个
Sorry, sorry. It's not something you see every day, is it,
自己的后脑勺
the back of your own head.
话说
Mind you,
我明白你为什么要戴帽子了
I can see why you wear a hat.
我不想显得虚荣 但是 你还是把帽子戴上吧
I don't want to seem vain, but could you keep that on?
你对我的塔迪斯做了什么
What have you done to my Tardis?
你把桌面主题给换了?
You've changed the desktop theme, haven't you.
这是什么? 珊瑚?
What's this one, coral?
比豹纹还要糟糕
Well It's worse than the leopard skin.
啊! 终于出场了 "智者眼镜"
Oh, and out they come, the brainy specs.
其实你根本不需要
You don't even need them.
你只是觉得戴着显得聪明
You just think they make you look a bit clever.
警报出现了 五级危险
That's an alert, level five,
说明这是时间冲撞
indicating a temporal collision.
就像两个塔迪斯合为一体
It's like two Tardises have merged,
可现在绝对只有一个塔迪斯
but there's definitely only one Tardis present.
就好像两个时区在塔迪斯中心互相抗衡
It's like two time zones or more at the heart of the Tardis.
这是个悖论
That's a paradox
这会在时空连续体中炸出一个洞 大小…
that could blow a hole in the space time continuum the size of.
大小正好相当于…比利时
Well, actually, the exact size of Belgium.
这好像也没那么夸张嘛 比利时?
That's a bit undramatic, isn't it? Belgium?
需要这个么?
Need this?
不用 我能行
No, I'm fine.
哦 当然了
Oh no, of course,
你一直都是赤手空拳的对吧
you liked to go hands free, didn't you,
就像在说 嘿 我是博士
like hey, I'm the Doctor.
我用瓶瓶罐罐和几根线就能拯救世界
I can save the universe using a kettle and some string.
瞧 我还戴着棵芹菜呢
And look at me, I'm wearing a vegetable.
你是谁?
Who are you?
仔细瞧瞧
Take a look.
噢 噢不
Oh. Oh, no.
噢 就是
Oh yes.
你是…不会吧
You're. Oh, no.
没错 我就是…
Here it comes. Yeah, I am.
—个粉丝!
A fan.
是的…什么?
Yeah. What?
现在十级了
Level ten, now.
坏了 再过两分钟就到比利时了
This is bad. Two minutes to Belgium.
你说什么呢 粉丝?
What do you mean, a fan?
我不是什么粉丝 我就是你
I'm not just a fan, I'm you.
好 你是我的头号粉丝
Okay, you're my biggest fan.
听着 其实很好理解
Look, its perfectly understandable.
我穿梭于时空之中
I go zooming around space and time,
到处拯救星球 对抗怪物…
saving planets, fighting monsters and being...
说实话 就像一个超凡英雄似的
well let's be honest, pretty sort of marvelous,
然后 很自然的 就会有人开始关注我
so naturally now and then people notice me.
建立他们小团体
Start up their little groups.
比如那个"琳达组织"
That LINDA lot.
你是他们的成员吗?
Are you one of them?
你是怎么进来的?
How did you get in here?
可不能让你们知道我的住址
Can't have you lot knowing where I live.
听好了 我就是你
Listen to me. I'm you, I'm you.
我是换了张新脸的你
I'm you with a new face.
好好看看这副骨架 博士
Check out this bone structure, Doctor,
因为总有一天 你得给它刮胡子
because one day you're going to be shaving it.
修道院钟声
The cloister bell!
是啊 正是时候 该我行动了
Right on time. That's my cue.
不出一分钟 我们就会制造出一个
In a minute we're going to create a black hole
足以吞噬整个宇宙的黑洞
strong enough to swallow the entire universe!
是啊 其实是我的错
Yeah, that's my fault, actually.
我在重建塔迪斯的时候 忘了打开防护罩了
I was rebuilding the Tardis, forgot to put the shields back up.
你的塔迪斯和我的塔迪斯…
Your Tardis and my Tardis,
不 是两个时间点上的同一个迪斯 撞到一块儿了
well the same Tardis at different points in its own timestream collided
就这样 差点就宇宙末曰了 瞧我这笨手笨脚的
and whoo, there you go, end of the universe, butterfingers.
不过不用担心 我很清楚接下来该怎么做
But don't worry, I know exactly how this all works out.
看好了
Watch.
释放热量缓冲器
Venting the thermobuffer,
拉动导航校准器
drawing the Helmic regulator,
最后一步 我们榨干那些塞顿晶体
and just to finish off, let's fry those Zeiton crystals.
你会炸掉塔迪斯的
You'll blow up the Tardis.
这是唯一的办法
I know I haven't.
谁告诉你的?
Who told you that?
你告诉我的!
You told me that.
超新星和黑洞在同一时刻产生
Supernova and black hole at the exact same instant.
外爆和内爆相互抵消
The explosion cancels out the implosion.
物质保持恒定
Pressure remains constant.
太机智了
It's brilliant.
简直太机智了
Far too brilliant.
我还没见过有谁能这样驾驶塔迪斯的
I've never met anyone else who could fly the Tardis like that.
抱歉了老兄 还没到时候
Sorry, mate, you still haven't.
你根本没有时间想出这样的方案
You didn't have time to work all that out.
连我都没法做到
Even I couldn't do it.
我没有想出来
I didn't work it out.
也不需要想
I didn't have to.
你记得怎么做
You remembered.
因为你会记住的
Because you will remember.
你会记得此时的我…
You remembered being me
看见此时的你做过
watching you doing that.
你知道要怎么做是因为…
You already knew what to do because
我看见你做了
I saw you do it.
时空错乱 因果倒转
Wibbly wobbly Timey wimey!
好了 两个塔迪斯正在分离
Right, Tardises are separating.
抱歉了 博士 时间到了
Sorry, Doctor, time's up.
该回到过去了
Back to long ago.
你现在应该到哪儿
Where are you now?
泥莎和提更? 赛博人和玛拉…
Nyssa and Tegan? Cybermen and Mara
戴者搞笑的帽子的时间领主以及法师?
and Time Lords in funny hats and the Master?
噢 对了 他最近又出现了 还是老样子
Oh, he just showed up again, same as ever.
不是吧…真的?
Oh no, really?
他还留着那糟糕的胡子吗?
Does he still have that rubbish beard?
不 这次没胡子了
No, no beard this time.
只是…多了个老婆
Well, a wife.
哦…看来我该走了
Oh, I seem to be off.
我还能说什么呢?
What can I say?
谢谢你 博士
Thank you, Doctor.
谢谢你
Thank you.
不用客气
I'm very welcome.
你知道吗
You know,
我很怀念还是你的时候
I love being you.
回想当初一开始的时候
Back when I first started at the very beginning,
我总想做一个惹不起的老头子
I was always trying to be old and grumpy and important,
就像你年轻时一样
like you do when you're young.
然后我成为了你
And then I was you,
到处乱跑 还玩板球
and it was all dashing about and playing cricket
一喊起来嗓子就变尖
and my voice going all squeaky when I shouted.
到现在还是这样子 尖嗓子 从你那儿继承的
I still do that, the voice thing. I got that from you.
哦 还有板鞋
Oh, and the trainers,
还有…
and
这个
Snap.
你知道为什么吗? 博士
Because you know what, Doctor?
因为你是我的博士
You were my Doctor.
寄意以明日
To days to come.
吾爱致往昔
All my love to long ago.
噢 博士
Oh, Doctor,
别忘了开启防护罩
remember to put your shields up.
什么?
What?
什么!
What!
(泰坦尼克号)
什么…?
What?